thesmartcrowd.com 2014-10-07

# Privacy Policy - Lionbridge

## Lionbridge Privacy Policy

This is a privacy policy for Lionbridge Technologies, Inc. Lionbridge has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate its firm commitment to privacy. The following discloses its information gathering and dissemination practices for www.lionbridge.com and other Internet web sites owned by Lionbridge.

Lionbridge invites you to contact Lionbridge if you have questions about this policy. You may contact Lionbridge by mail at the following address:

1050 Winter Street, Suite 2300  
Waltham, MA 02451 USA

You may contact Lionbridge by e-mail at [privacy@lionbridge.com](mailto:privacy@lionbridge.com).  
You may also call Lionbridge at +1 781.434.6000.

## Dispute Resolution and Privacy Seals

Please send an e-mail to [privacy@lionbridge.com](mailto:privacy@lionbridge.com).

## Data Collection

P3P policies declare the data they collect in groups (also referred to as “statements”). This policy contains three data groups. The data practices of each group will be explained separately.

**Group “Basic Information”**

In general, you can visit the Lionbridge website without providing personal information, but there are times when Lionbridge will request personal information. Personal information is information that individually identifies you, such as your name, telephone number, physical address or email address. Lionbridge may also gather personal information in connection with any contests Lionbridge offers or if you participate in one of its online communities.

Lionbridge Technologies, Inc. is a U.S. based company with offices throughout the world. It is possible that any personally identifiable information collected from you may be transferred to other Lionbridge sites located outside your country of residence that may not have equivalent laws and rules regarding privacy and data protection. We are committed to the security of personally identifiable information and we take reasonable precautions to maintain that protection. Although we use physical and administrative procedures to attempt to safeguard personally identifiable information, we cannot guarantee that it is completely secure from people who might attempt to evade security measures or intercept transmissions over the Internet.

Lionbridge collects and uses your information in order to give you better service, to provide you with convenient access to its products and services and to make its website more useful to you. The contact information Lionbridge collects is used, in part, to deliver information about Lionbridge and its partners and promotional material to you. It is also used to contact you when necessary. Information collected through the use of cookies is used to evaluate and improve its website and to help diagnose problems with its server. Lionbridge will only use (such use including disclosure) your personal information without notice when it believes the use to be required by law or regulation, or necessary to protect or defend the rights or property of Lionbridge, the safety of the public or the users of its site, or if you have provided Lionbridge with prior consent to do so (see “Opt-In” below).

Lionbridge may collect the following information:

  * URL of requested resource
  * Full IP address
  * HTTP request method
  * Data bytes in response
  * Response status code
  * User agent information
  * Last URL requested by the user

This data will be used for the following purposes:

  * Completion and support of the current activity
  * Web site and system administration

This data will be used by Lionbridge and its agents.

**Group “Cookies”**

Lionbridge collects the following information:

  * HTTP cookies

This data will be used for the following purposes:

  * Completion and support of the current activity.
  * Web site and system administration.

This data will be used by Lionbridge and its agents.

The following explanation is provided for why this data is collected:

Lionbridge sets a cookie when you arrive so that, IF you should register or request a contact, Lionbridge can capture the URL of the Web site that referred you to us. If you do not register or make a request, that information will never be linked to any personal information. No other data is captured in the cookie. Registering to access content on the Lionbridge Knowledge Center sets a second cookie that allows you to log in quickly the next time you wish to download white papers or demos.

**Group “Registration”**

Lionbridge collects the following information:

  * Online contact information

At the user’s option, Lionbridge may also collect the following data:

  * User’s Job Title
  * Name of User’s Employer
  * Given Name (First Name)
  * Family Name (Last Name)
  * Business mailing address
  * Telephone Number

This data will be used for the following purposes:

  * Completion and support of the current activity.
  * Web site and system administration.
  * Telemarketing.

This data will be used by Lionbridge and its agents. In addition, the following types of entities will receive this information:

  * Others following the same practices. The user is allowed to opt-out of this data sharing.

The following explanation is provided for why this data is collected:

This information is collected when you register to download white papers and demos, or request to be contacted by Lionbridge. A Lionbridge Sales or Marketing professional may contact you based on the information you provide. Lionbridge also reserves the future possibility of sharing lists with Marketing or Alliance partners, who share equivalent Privacy policies.

## Opt-Out Policy

If, at any time, you change your mind about receiving information from Lionbridge or about sharing your information with third parties, please send Lionbridge a request specifying your new choice. Simply send your request to [opt-out@lionbridge.com](mailto:opt-out@lionbridge.com).

## Cookies

Cookies are a technology which can be used to provide you with tailored information from a Web site. A cookie is an element of data that a Web site can send to your browser, which may then store it on your system. You can set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether to accept it.

Our site makes use of cookies. Cookies are used for the following purposes:

  * Site administration
  * Completing the user’s current activity

## Privacy

Lionbridge currently contracts with several online partners to help manage and optimize its Internet business and communications. Lionbridge uses the services of a marketing company to help it measure the effectiveness of its advertising and how visitors use its site. To do this, Lionbridge uses Web beacons and cookies provided by its marketing company on this site. The type of information Lionbridge collects includes how visitors find its site, the pages they visit, their activities, and where they exit the site. By supplementing its records, this information helps Lionbridge learn things like what pages are most attractive to its visitors and which of its services most interest its customers. Although its marketing company logs the information coming from its site on its behalf, Lionbridge controls how that data may and may not be used. If you do not wish to help Lionbridge learn how to improve its site, products and offers, you can Opt-out of this website analysis tool by emailing Lionbridge at [privacy@lionbridge.com](mailto:privacy@lionbridge.com).

## Security

You are prohibited from violating, or attempting to violate, the security of the Lionbridge Network. Any violations may result in criminal and civil liabilities to you. Lionbridge will investigate any alleged violations and will cooperate with law enforcement agencies if a criminal violation is suspected. Examples of violations of the security of the Lionbridge network include, without limitation, the following:

  * Accessing data not intended for you
  * Logging into a server or account which you are not authorized to access
  * Attempting to probe, scan, or test the vulnerability of a system or network
  * Breaching security or authentication measures without proper authorization
  * Attempting to interfere with service to any user, host, or network including, without limitation, by means of “overloading,” “flooding,” “mailbombing,” or “crashing”
  * Taking any action in order to obtain services to which you are not entitled

## Illegal Use

The Lionbridge network may only be used for lawful purposes. For example, you may not use the Lionbridge network to create, transmit, distribute, or store material that:

  * Violates a trademark, copyright, trade secret, or other intellectual property rights of others
  * Violates the privacy, publicity, or other personal rights of others
  * Impairs the privacy of communications
  * Contains obscene or pornographic content
  * May be threatening, abusive, or hateful
  * Violates export control laws or regulations
  * Encourages conduct that would constitute a criminal offense or give rise to civil liability
  * Causes technical disturbances to the Lionbridge Network, including, but not limited to, introduction of viruses, worms, or other destructive mechanisms
  * Violates reasonable regulations of Lionbridge or other service providers with respect to the Lionbridge Network
  * Assists or permits any persons in engaging in any of the activities described above
  * Constitutes deceptive online marketing

If you become aware of any such activities, you are obligated to immediately notify Lionbridge and take all other appropriate actions to cause such activities to cease.

## Unsolicited Communications (“Spam”)

Posting the same or similar unsolicited e-mail messages, bulk commercial advertising, or informal announcements to one or more groups (known as “Spam”) is prohibited. Spam is not only annoying to Internet users, it seriously affects the efficiency and cost-effectiveness of the Lionbridge Network. These unsolicited messages can increase costs by clogging the Lionbridge Network, rendering your web site inaccessible, and potentially leading to down time of your mission-critical Internet applications.

In addition, both Usenet and e-mail users may not:

  * send or post e-mail messages which are excessive and/or intended to harass or annoy others
  * continue to send e-mail to a recipient that has indicated that he/she does not wish to receive it
  * send e-mail with forged TCP/IP packet header information
  * intentionally omit, delete, forge, or misrepresent transmission information, including headers and return addresses
  * take any other actions intended to cloak the your identity or contact information

## Content

Lionbridge exercises no control over, and accepts no responsibility for, the content of the information passing through the Lionbridge network, including content provided on any third-party web sites linked to the Lionbridge network. Any web site links are provided as Internet navigation tools for information purposes only and not as an endorsement by Lionbridge of the contents of such web sites. Lionbridge does not adopt, nor warrant the accuracy of, the content of any linked web site and undertakes no responsibility to update the content. Use of any information obtained via the Lionbridge network is at your own risk.

Lionbridge does not screen communications and is not responsible for screening or monitoring content used by you.

## Consequences of Unacceptable Use

Lionbridge reserves the right to suspend or terminate access to the Lionbridge network upon notice of a violation of this Policy.

Indirect or attempted violations of this Policy, and actual or attempted violations by a third-party on behalf of you, shall be considered violations of this Policy by you. Furthermore, it is a violation of this policy to use the services of another provider for the purposes of facilitating any of the activities described above if such use of another provider’s service could reasonably be expected to affect the Lionbridge network.
